minyanville.com 2019-06-06

# Minyanville Privacy Statement

**MINYANVILLE.COM PRIVACY STATEMENT**

The Privacy Statement was last updated November 4, 2009. 

Minyanville Media, Inc. is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following statement to understand how your personal information will be treated as you use the Minyanville.com website. The Minyanville.com and MinyanLand.com (together “Minyanville.com”) websites are owned and operated by Minyanville Media, Inc. 

**A. Gathering of Information**

Minyanville.com collects personally identifying information from users of its websites as follows. 

**Personal Information**

Minyanville.com web servers automatically collect information about a site user's IP address, browser type, and referrer by reading this information from the user's browser (information automatically provided by every user's browser). This information is collected in a database and used -- in an aggregated, anonymous manner -- in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our website. This information is automatically logged by most websites. 

In addition, we may ask you for additional information when you register to receive a newsletter so we can better understand our user base to constantly upgrade and improve the Minyanville service. You always have the option not to provide the additional information we request. If you choose not to provide the additional information we request, you can still visit most of the Minyanville.com website, but you may be unable to access certain options and services. 

**Browser Level Information -- Cookies**

A cookie is a data file that certain websites write to your computer's hard drive when you visit such sites. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user identification code, that the site uses to track the pages you have visited. Minyanville.com uses cookies solely to track user traffic patterns throughout the Minyanville.com website. We use this data on an anonymous basis and we do not correlate this information with personal data of any user. The acceptance of cookies allows the subscriber to experience a more streamlined and/or enhanced navigation to the content on the site. 

Most website browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our website, you may not be able to use certain features of the site. 

**B. Use of Information**

All information collected by Minyanville.com is for the building of a subscriber database to validate used IDs and passwords (in such instances where they may be required) as well as to solicit sales or offerings of additional Minyanville products. The Minyanville database of its website’s users will not be sold or shared with third parties except when we believe that the law requires it or a regulatory entity requests it to protect other users of the Minyanville.com sites or in emergency or extenuating circumstances. 

One of our goals in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our website. We achieve this goal by, among other things, providing interactive communications, such as our electronic newsletters to the email address that you provide us, and developing future editorial content based on your interests. To develop content targeted to your interests, we use aggregated user information to determine which areas of our website users prefer based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but instead how well each page or content area performs overall. 

Minyanville.com derives revenue from advertising. In order to attract and retain advertisers we may use the aggregated, anonymous information that we gather (as well as information from third-party market researchers) to describe our services to partners and to assist our advertisers and sponsors to better understand our audience. 

We may use third-party advertisers to serve ads and collect information when you visit Minyanville.com. When online advertisements are displayed to you, one or more cookies may be placed on your computer. Some of these companies may use information (not including personally identifiable information such as your name or email address) about your visits to our website and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

We do not disclose personally identifying information about our users. 

Minyanville.com may also disclose information about our users when we believe, in good faith, that the disclosure is required by law. 

When you are on an area of Minyanville.com and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Minyanville.com as well as business partners and vendors providing hosting and other services for Minyanville.com. If you do not want your information to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of your information by not using that particular service. These parties, as well as advertisers who contract directly with a third-party service to serve their advertisements, may set their own cookies. 

In addition, any personally identifiable information provided by our users as part of an advertiser promotion online may be provided directly to advertisers. 

Please be aware that advertisers or websites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those parties and websites linked to Minyanville.com are not covered by this privacy statement. Minyanville.com users should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards, that information may be collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others. 

This statement may change from time to time, so please check back periodically. 

_© 2014 Minyanville Media, Inc._

 **DEFINITIONS:**

IP address: Every computer connected to the Internet has a numeric address called an “IP address.” This may or may not correspond uniquely to a particular computer. In some cases, IP addresses can be resolved to domain names, which may indicate a site visitor's Internet service provider, employer, university, etc. As part of its database analysis, Minyanville.com resolves IP addresses to domain names. 

Browser type: A user’s browser is a software program running on a computer that allows users to access documents on the World Wide Web. Browsers can be either text or graphic. They read HTML coded pages that reside on a server and interpret the coding into what the user sees as web pages. Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer are examples of browsers. Browser type typically discloses hardware platform, operating system, and browser software and version. 

Referrer: The referrer is the URI of the Internet resource or page that causes a browser to request a page or image from Minyanville.com servers. 

### WHAT'S POPULAR IN THE VILLE
